# 'assin Ben Alla

□ (+31) 616093622 | ■ yassinbenallal@hotmail.com | 回 YasBenAll | 面 yassinbenallal

# Summary\_

During my Bachelor's degree in Information Science at the University of Amsterdam, I gained extensive experience in the field of data science using the programming languages Python and SQL. Since then, I have applied my programming knowledge alongside my academic coursework by building web scrapers for e-commerce businesses and engaging in web development using React. I am currently pursuing my Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence at the Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam and working as a Student Developer at the University of Amsterdam. I am experienced in using scientific software in Python, such as NumPy, Pandas, and PyTorch.

## Skills\_\_\_\_

**DevOps** Linux, Git

Back-end Python, SQL, Flask, Firebase, GraphQL

Front-end React, Next.js

Programming Python, SQL, JavaScript, R **Languages** Dutch, English, German, French

# Work Experience

### **University of Amsterdam**

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

DEVELOPER

June 2023 - present

• Working on progressing the development of a chatbot toolkit for experimental research.

#### **University of Amsterdam**

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

RESEARCH ASSISTANT July 2021 - July 2023

· Programming social robotics experiments at the Amsterdam School of Communication Research (ASCoR), primarily using Python.

#### Oxaigen DATA ENGINEER INTERN

Amsterdam, The Netherlands July 2022 - September 2022

• Building data pipelines using dbt (SQL) for AI tools that will be used in the healthcare industry.

• Building APIs using GraphQL.

#### **University of Amsterdam**

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

**TEACHING ASSISTANT** 

October 2019 - July 2021

- Organizing working groups where I support students on assignment work about topics such as statistical analysis (SPSS) and programming (Python).
- · Grading homework.

### **Education**

#### Vrije Universiteit Amsterdam

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Aug. 2021 - present

• GPA: 7.8

· Following the Deepening AI track.

#### **University of Amsterdam**

MSc in Artificial Intelligence

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

**BSc in Information Science** 

Aug. 2018 - Aug. 2021

- GPA: 77
- During my minor Data Science at VU Amsterdam, I deepened my knowledge on various topics in the field of data science, such as Data Structures and Algorithms and Information Retrieval.

# **Committees**

Study Association STORM

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

# **Honors & Awards**

July 2023 Kaggle Award for the Machine Learning Reproducibilty Challenge

YASSIN BEN ALLAL · CV NOVEMBER 7, 2023



#### Web development The Netherlands

FREELANCER

- Dec. 2020 present • Developing websites using Next.js and Firebase.
- Building web scrapers for e-commerce businesses.

# **Licenses Certifications**

#### France Éducation international

DIPLÔME D'ÉTUDES EN LANGUE FRANÇAISE, B2

Issued Mar. 2016 · No Expiration Date

• Certification of French-language abilities on an intermediate level (B2) for non-native speakers of French administered by France Education International (France Éducation international or FEI) for France's Ministry of Education.

#### dbt labs

DBT FUNDAMENTALS

Issued jul. 2022 · Expires Jul. 2024

• Finished the the online dbt Fundamentals v2 course and passed the end of course quiz, which demonstrates fundamental understanding of models, sources, tests, docs and deployment in dbt.